SAIMA SHARLEEN ISLAM

→ +880-1827537100

saimasharleen10@gmail.com
saimasharleen

saimasharleen

saimasharleen saimasharleen

Objectives

A diligent, amiable, and articulate individual who is passionate about building up a flourishing research career across AI, Machine Learning and it's applications, Data Science, Computer Vision. I have mainly worked with machine learning algorithms and it applications in the field of data science. I bring with me, my strong passion for technology and quick learning capability.

Education

American International University-Bangladesh

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science & Software Engineering (CGPA: 3.42 /4.00)

May 2016 – Feb 2020 Dhaka, Bangladesh

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Work Experience

Cystem Arts Apr 2020 — Sep 2021

Software Engineer

• Assisted in development of the front end of a client's website.

Collaborated with team members using version control systems such as Git to do the modifications.

American International University-Bangladesh

Sep 2019 — Dec 2019

Teaching Assistant

• Assisted the students in project for Advanced Topics In Programming III course

• Performed regular data entry tasks on students' evaluation grades

Battery Low Interactive Ltd.

Aug 2019 — Nov 2019

Intern, Web Development and Content Writing

Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Collaborated with team members using version control systems such as Git to complete the assign tasks.
- Created different contents for the company.

Research Interests

Machine Learning, Deep Learning & its applications, Computer Vision, Medical Informatics

Research Experience

Application of Machine Learning Algorithms to Predict the Thyroid Risk: An Experimental Comparative Study

• Compared various algorithms for increasing the accuracy of thyroid disease prediction using the UCI thyroid data collection. (Submitted to IEEE Access)

UG Thesis: Human Detection in Crowd using Video Surveillance System

• Using YOLO detected human in crowd in AIUB premises.

Publications

Conference Paper:

• Saima Sharleen Islam, Md Mahmudul Hasan Bhuiyan, Zahiduddin Ahmed, and Md Al-Amin. "An Empirical Survey on Crowdsourcing-Based Data Management Techniques." In Proceedings of the International Conference on Computing Advancements, pp. 1-7. 2020.

Standardized Tests

International English Language Test (IELTS):

Aggregate: 7, Listening: 8, Reading: 7, Speaking: 7, Writing: 6

Technical Skills

Languages: Python, C, C++, Java, c#

Database: SQL (MySQL,Oracle,Postgres), MongoDB

Tools: Git, VS Code, Jupyter Notebook, Google Colab, Overleaf, TeXworks, PyCharm, Mendeley

Libraries: Scikit-Learn, Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, OpenCV Web Technologies: Laravel, PHP, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Nodejs

Academic Projects

Extra Food Distribution Management System | HTML, CSS, Java script, Bootstrap, PHP, My SQL

- Overview: A platform for the Restaurant owner, Volunteer, Admin, Event Manager and General User. The owner can post for leftover foods, and a volunteer will pick up the foods and later will donate food in a specific location.
- Github Link: https://github.com/saimasharleen/Extra-Food-Distribution-Management-System-Web-Technologies-

Nirjhor $\mid c++, opengl$

- Overview: Nirjhor is basically a scenery-based project using opengl.
- Github Link: https://github.com/saimasharleen/Nirjhor-Graphics-Project-

Fashion $\mid bootstrap, css, javascript, html$

- Overview: Fashion is basically a web design project.
- Github Link: https://github.com/saimasharleen/Fashion-Web-Design

Online Courses

- 1. IBM Data Science Professional Certificate:(On Going)
- 2. Data Science Math Skills-Duke University: (On Going)

Awards & Achievements

• Ada Lovelace Datathon 2021

Team Position: 8th Team Name: Panda-15

Standing Link: https://www.kaggle.com/c/alc-datathon-2021/leaderboard

• National Girls' Programming Contest 2018

Team Name: AIUB Incognito

Standing Link: https://algo.codemarshal.org/contests/ngpc18/standings

• The Duke of Edinburgh's International Award

The Bronze Standard

• Hult Prize at AIUB

2nd Runner Up

• World Literature Centre Book Reading Program

Winner

Extracurricular Activities

Firefox at AIUB

June 2018 – Feb 2020

Club Lead

American International University-Bangladesh

- Managed executive board of 8 members and ran weekly meetings to oversee progress in essential parts of the chapter.
- Led chapter of 50+ members to work towards goals that improve and promote opensource and improve community service.

References

Md. Saef Ullah Miah

Md. Al-Amin

Lecturer

Department of Computer Science
American International University-Bangladesh

⋈ alamin@aiub.edu

Dr. Dip Nandi

Professor and Director
Faculty of Science and Technology
American International University-Bangladesh

⋈ dip.nandi@aiub.edu